westernu.edu 2017-11-29

# Privacy Policy | Resources - Western University of Health Sciences

### Privacy Policy

Western University reserves the right to use and implement cookies or allow its affiliated entities to do so. The University does not control, nor have any access to, the cookie information affiliated entities may collect. If a Web visitor chooses not to accept these cookies, the browsing experience on some sections of the University’s site and its related sites may be diminished, and some features may not work as intended.

Western University’s Web site also contains links to external sites. Western University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these Web sites.

In order to better serve the needs of site visitors, Western University keeps track of certain traffic data. These include the platform used (e.g., Macintosh or PC), browser type (e.g., Netscape or Microsoft Internet Explorer), IP address (or Internet Protocol address, which identifies the visitor’s service provider, but not the visitor personally) and the previous URL (Uniform Resource Locator, or Web address) visited by the visitor before reaching the University’s site. None of these disclose personal information, and the information they do reveal is used exclusively for internal administrative purposes. Western University does not collect and evaluate this information for specific individuals. Western University’s Web servers do not automatically record e-mail addresses of the visitors.

Western University’s search engine collects aggregate search terms for internal reporting and targeted advertising. Western University monitors aggregate visitor activity on the sites and shares this information with external entities, but at no stage are individual users personally identifiable, nor is any personal information divulged.

Western University is also involved in organizing and conducting public events, and may, from time to time, use the Web to promote these events and invite prospective attendees to supply certain information about themselves. This demographic information will not be disclosed to any third parties without the consent of the individual or organization concerned.

Web users are sometimes asked to supply personal information, including name, contact information and credit card number, mostly for, but not restricted to, Western University online stores. Billing information will be used solely for billing purposes and will not otherwise be disclosed.

Whenever a visitor’s identity is requested, the purpose of the inquiry will be indicated before the information is requested. Western University maintains a strict “No-Spam” policy, which means the University does not sell, rent, or otherwise give e-mail addresses to a third party without consent or as permitted by this Privacy Policy.

Except as stated above, Western University will not send e-mail to Web visitors that they have not agreed to receive.  
Western University will disclose personal information and/or an IP address when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to cooperate with the investigations of purported unlawful activities and conform to the edicts of the law or comply with any legal process.

When an order is placed online, Western University scrambles personal data and credit card information using SSL encryption technology. This makes it virtually impossible for information to be stolen or intercepted while being transferred across the Internet. Upon receipt, orders are encrypted until processed.

By accessing the Western University sites, Web visitors consent to the collection and use of information by Western University as specified above. If the University decides to change its privacy policy, it will post those changes on this page to disclose to visitors what information is collected, how it is used, and under what circumstances it will be divulged.

Click for more information on the [Privacy Act of 1974](http://www.usdoj.gov/opcl/privacyact1974.htm).

Queries or questions about this privacy policy should be directed to the Webmaster at [webmaster@westernu.edu](mailto:webmaster@westernu.edu).
